# JHON DEIBER DIAZ PARRA

Montréal QC, Canada | (514)3461672 | jhondeiberd@gmail.com Portfolio | Linkedin | Github

**English** - Professional working proficiency French - Elementary proficiency Spanish - Native or bilingual proficiency

Environment: Kottlin - Android

### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a creative person in problem solving and analytical thinking. During my studies, I have learned different technologies and programming languages, I am passionate about learning, teamwork and I want to get a great experience as a programmer and thus be able to contribute to the needs of companies and their customers. Throughout my career, I have been involved in large-scale complex projects, reengineering of functionalities and interfaces. I believe that innovation and continuous improvement is a success factors for organizations, so I tirelessly insist on applying these criteria in every initiative in which I have participated.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Web: HTML5, CSS3, Node.is, React, Web services API

Programming languages: Java, Python, GO, C#, C++, PHP, JavaScript, Transact-SQL

Mobile technologies: Kotlin, Flutter Control version: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket,

Project management: Scrum, Kamban, Trello, Planner Database: SQL server, MySql, MariaBD, PostgreSQL

Business Management Software: ERP Microsoft Dynamics, WMS Arcante, PLM Porini, ICG POS

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Application personal Budget Android**

Application developed in Kottlin - Android to manage a personal budget, where the user adds income, expenses and as a result shows a personal balance. It allows adding, editing, deleting transactions and is multilingual.

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Jhon Diaz Code

# Application full-stack Manager favorite music albums

Environment: Node.js - ReactJs - PostgreSQL Development of a web application for the user to manage a list of favorites, searching, adding, and deleting. It was built with a Back-end server using Node is + Express for the REST APIs that manage the PostgreSQL database. The Front-end server is a React is that request the user requirements with RESTful APIs for the Discogs Music. My role in this project was developing the Back-end part.

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Anuj Narang - Jhon Diaz **Code** 

#### **MVC** application for managing contacts

**Environment:** SQL server Application developed in C# for contact management, a graphical interface that allows you to create new contacts, edit existing ones and delete them, these data are stored in text files. In this project worked. In this project, we worked on distributing parts of the menu for the project. In this project, we distributed parts of the menu for the project, and each one coded and tested his part.

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Ricardo Castano - Jhon Diaz Code

#### Administrador de la base de datos ERP

**Environment: SQL server** I Developed and programed in Transact-SQL to rebuild and reorganize indexes and update statistics, backups to maintain optimal performance of the company's ERP database.

Associated with: ISI College

# TRAINING

Programming and Web Technologies, Attestation of College Studies	2021 - Present
Institut Supérieur d'Informatique – Montreal, Canada Francisation Level 2 FIA109-3, French studies	2022 - Present
Centre Social d'aide aux Immigrants - CSAI – Montreal, Canada	2022 1 103011
Production engineer, Bachelor's Degree	2008 - 2013
Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas, Bogotá - Colombia	
Industrial technology, Diploma of Vocational Studies Fundación Cidca, Bogotá - Colombia	2002 - 2005
Taridadion Glada, Bogota Golombia	

### CERTIFICATIONS

Analyzing data with Power BI, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)	2020 - 2020
SQL 2016 Database Development, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)	2019 - 2020
Developing C# - ASP.NET Core MVC, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)	2019 - 2019
Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting – Remote	

Jhon Deiber Diaz Parra (514) 3461672 jhondeiberd@gmail.com

# Object-oriented programming paradigm Database Administrator (DBA)

Fundación Carlos Slim- Remote

2021 **-** 2021 2017 **-** 2018

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

### **Applications and Database Manager ERP**

2017 - 2020

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Implemented agile methodologies for the execution and follow-up of projects and developments in Dynamics ERP.
- Supported my team with debugging code in the Dynamics ERP AOT for bug fixes.
- Developed database queries for incident resolution and analysis.
- Monitor database performance, Define users and enable data distribution.
- Database maintenance, indexes, re-indexing, statistics, locks, back-up
- Collaborated with area managers and third-level service companies to identify and resolve problems, coordinated system requirements and created project schedules. Planned and executed annual budget for ERP improvement.
- Planned, implemented and supervised IT technology solutions to ensure satisfactory fulfillment of end-user requirements, implementation and support in a productive environment.
- Coordinated the development of virtual training material for the users' application

# OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Landscaper 2021 – Present

Boardwalk, Montréal QC, Canada

- Responsible for painting common areas of assigned buildings.
- · Responsible for mowing the lawns around the buildings.
- · Support the maintenance and concierges teams when necessary.

# **Applications Professional ERP**

2008 - 2017

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Escalated problems to the Technical Specialist Level III's or above within the support structure.
- Led the definition and formation of plans for applications aimed to master users' knowledge.
- Performed test runs for approval and implementation of developments in a production environment.
- Enhanced and maintained ERP functionalities and execute upcoming projects.
- Implemented and deployed ERP's standard modules and local functionalities.
- · Optimized processes and procedures in the ERP
- Developed virtual training material amended to extend the ERP modules.

# **Production Planning Analyst**

2006 - 2008

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Implemented Material Requirements Planning (MRP) methodology for product production
- Designed and configured technical sheets and spreadsheets for clothing products.
- Calculated the manufacturing route and the cost of the bill of materials for the garments.
- Applied engineering industrialization methods and plans to improve the manufacturing process to optimize operating costs.
- Optimized raw material inventories and allocation based on collection designs.

# **Production Engineering Analyst**

2003 - 2006

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Designed and enhance workload balancing for production plants.
- Implemented engineering methods and time analysis for the plans' workstations.
- · Prepared operational listings for garments products.
- Designed and implement standards time for garments operations.
- Identified and improved bottlenecks for production modules.
- Prepared efficiency reports and control the unproductive time of the plant.